A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) files FA740
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Conferences, 1949-1967; IV; 10.8 Cubic Feet 9 boxes.
  - Conferences, Not Fund Supported, 1949-1964; 2; 4.8 Cubic Feet 4 boxes.; 4 boxes.
    - UN/UNESCO Conference on Social Aspects of Technical Assistance Programs for Economic Development, 1953 (Box 4 (49743))
    - University College of the West Indies Conference on the Institute of Education, 1960-1961 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Utah Conference on Higher Education, 1958 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Western Graduate Deans, 1957 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, 1959 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Where Will the College Teachers of the Future Come From? - Conference at Barnard College, 1957 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Williamsburg International Assembly, 1957 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Conference on the Goals of Women Related to Higher Education, 1955 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Worchester Conference, 1955-1956 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Columbia UniversityTeacher's College Work Conference on Sec.Ed., 1958 (Box 4 (49743))
    - Work Conference on Secondary Education [2 Folders], 1958 (Box 4 (49743))
    - World Federation of Organizations of the Teaching Profession, 1957 (Box 4 (49743))
- Publications, 1952-1967; V; 2.4 Cubic Feet 2 boxes.; 2 boxes.
  This series consists of publications prepared and distributed by the Fund for the Advancement of Education. The publications include monographs on Fund initiatives and TFAE annual and bi-annual reports.
  - Bridging the Gap Between School and College, 1953 (Box 1 (49744))
  - The Changing School Curriculum (2 copies), 1966 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Copyright and Intellectual Property - Julius Marke, 1967 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Education: A Reappraisal (2 copies), 1962 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Education and American History (2 copies), 1965 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Encouraging the Excellent - Elizabeth Paschal (2 copies), 1960 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Fortifying Higher Education: A Story of College Self Study - Robert Donaldson, 1959 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Four Case Studies of Programed Instruction, 1964 (Box 1 (49744))
  - The Graduate School Today and Tomorrow - Reflections for the Profession's Consideration (2 copies), 1955 (Box 1 (49744))
  - The Great Awakening, Including a Plan for Education Leadership, 1958 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Learning by Television (2 copies), 1966 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Letter to a College President: On the Need for Long-Range Planning (2 copies), 1963 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Needed: A Ten Year Budget - Sidney Tickton, 1961 (Box 1 (49744))
  - New Directions in Teacher Education - Paul Woodring (2 copies), 1957 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Programed Instruction Today and Tomorrow - Wilbur Schramm (3 copies, 1 in German; 2 Folders), 1962 (Box 1 (49744))
  - The Role of Education in American History (2 copies), 1957 (Box 1 (49744))
  - School Curriculum Reform (2 copies), 1964 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Schools for Tomorrow: An Educator's Blueprint - Alexander J. Stoddard (2 copies), 1957 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Teachers for Tomorrow - Bulletin No.2, 1955 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Teaching by Television (2 copies), 1959 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Teaching by Television (2 copies), 1960 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Teaching Salaries Then and Now: A 50 Year Comparison with Other Occupations and Industries - Beardsley Ruml and Sidney Tickton (2 copies), 1956 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Teaching Salaries Then and Now: A Second Look - Sidney Tickton (2 copies), 1961 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Televised College Courses - John W. Meaney (2 copies), 1962 (Box 1 (49744))
  - Tomorrow's Professors - John S. Diekhoff, [1959] (Box 1 (49744))
  - Ways to Justice, 1955 (Box 1 (49744))
  - The Year-Round Campus Catches On - Sidney Tickton, 1963 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - Annual Report, 1951-1952 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1952-1954 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1954-1956, 1957 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1957-1959 (2 copies) (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1959-1961 (Supplementing Decade of Experiment) (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1961-1962, 1963 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - A Report for 1962-1964, 1965 (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - Continuting Liberal Education - Report for 1955-1957 (2 copies) (Box 1 (49744))
  - TFAE - Continuing Liberal Education - Report for 1957-1959 (2 copies), 1961 (Box 2 (49745))
  - TFAE - A Decade of Experiement, 1951-1961 (Box 2 (49745))
  - The Battle of the Curriculum - C. Scott Fletcher (speech), 1958 (Box 2 (49745))
  - Ingenuity Needed for Critical Educational Problems - Alvin Eurich (speech), 1957 (Box 2 (49745))
  - Teacher Education - Edited by Elmer R. Smith [Contributor: Alvin C. Eurich], 1962 (Box 2 (49745))
  - Universal Higher Education - Earl J. McGrath [Contributor: Frank H. Bowles], 1966 (Box 2 (49745))
  - Saturday Review - Classroom TV Enters a New Era [Monthly supplement sponsored by TFAE], 1961 (Box 2 (49745))
  - The National Program in the Use of Television in the Public Schools - A Report on the First Year, 1957-1958, 1959 (Box 2 (49745))
  - The National Program in the Use of Television in the Public Schools - A Report on the Second Year, 1958-1959, 1960 (Box 2 (49745))
  - The National Program in the Use of Television in the Public Schools - A Report on the Third Year, 1961 (Box 2 (49745))
  - The Negro and the Schools - Harry Ashmore [Forward by Owen Roberts, Chairman of TFAE Board of Directors], 1954 (Box 2 (49745))